A Guide to the Papers of Base Hospital 41 1905-2009
Claude Moore Health Sciences Library
Historical Collections, Claude Moore Health Sciences Library, University of Virginia
Papers of Base Hospital 41 1905-2009
Historical Collections, Claude Moore Health Sciences Library, University of Virginia
MS-17
1.75 linear ft. (4 boxes, ca. 1100 items)
Administrative Information
Access Restrictions
Collection is open to research.
Acquisition Information
Collected by Bernard P. Chamberlain and other members of Base Hospital 41.
Biographical/Historical Information
After the United States entered World War I, Dr. William H. Goodwin contacted the Red Cross in Washington D.C. in regard to organizing a base hospital at the University of Virginia. The authority to organize a hospital was granted, and UVa President E. A. Alderman recommended the appointment of Dr. Goodwin as director. On June 23, 1917 the hospital was assigned number 41. Dr. Goodwin learned he would need to recruit all the supporting staff of the hospital as well as its doctors and nurses. It was also his responsibility to acquire funds to purchase the supplies for the hospital as the War Department had determined that only fully equipped and supplied hospitals would be accepted for active service. Dr. Goodwin contacted the Benevolent and Protective Order of Elks of the U.S, which had collected from its members a substantial amount of money to be used as a war relief fund. The Elks agreed to furnish all of the needed funds and deposited the money with the Red Cross.
Well-qualified officers were selected as well as 149 enlisted men, 49 of them UVa alumni or students. On March 5, 1918, the detachment entrained for Camp Sevier, South Carolina, where it was organized by Major (later Lieutenant Colonel) Julian M. Cabell and no longer considered a Red Cross unit. Two months later after intensive training, Cabell reported to the Surgeon General that the unit was ready for overseas duty.
Finally on July 26, 1918, Base Hospital 41 arrived in St. Denis, France, near Paris at the park of l'Ecole de la Legion d'Honneur. The hospital was established in the building used for schooling children of the members of the Legion of Honor. Secured for Base Hospital 41 by the American Red Cross, it was a stately eighteenth century building in a lovely park setting. The school dormitories were converted into hospital wards, and by August 12th Base Hospital 41 was ready to receive patients, meaning that the wards, operating rooms, laboratories, and ancillary services were set to function.
The first convoy consisted of 136 patients who were treated promptly and efficiently. The capacity of the building was soon reached and new tent wards were constantly being pitched in the park. Eventually the hospital was equipped to care for 600 patients in the building and another 2200 in the tent wards. One of the most stressful periods was from 4 PM on October 19, 1918, to 10 AM on October 22, 1918, when 693 patients were admitted to an already full hospital.
Base Hospital 41 had to contend with the influenza epidemic of 1918. A considerable percentage of both personnel and patients were attacked, and four staff members died of pneumonia following flu. Although not at the front, the unit also suffered from several air raids.
When the Armistice was signed on November 11, 1918, nearly three thousand patients were in the hospital. Two and a half months later, all the patients had been evacuated, and the hospital ceased to function. The unit was demobilized on May 1, 1919.
Scope and Content
Of unique relevance to the University of Virginia Health System is the Base Hospital 41 collection. It includes; photographs and negatives of Base Hospital 41; photocopies of photos held by the National Library of Medicine, History of Medicine; Base Hospital 41 newsletters; news clippings; medals; excerpts from Glenn B. Updike's wartime diary; documents relating to Chief Nurse Margaret Cowling; a history of Base Hospital 41; "The University of Virginia Base Hospital Forty-One," by the Commanding Officer, Julian M. Cabell; a historical sketch of Base Hospital 41 by Deming J. Shear; correspondence and photos related to reunions; and other archival material.
Arrangement
The arrangement is numerical by box and folder.
Contents List
- "The University of Virginia Base Hospital Forty-One" by the Commanding Officer [Julian M. Cabell] 1925, original (Box-folder 001-001A)
- "The University of Virginia Base Hospital Forty-One" by the Commanding Officer [Julian M. Cabell] 1925, photocopied book, 2 copies 64 pp. (Box-folder 001-001B)
- "Historical Sketch of Base Hospital 41" by Deming J. Shear; includes a "Red Cross Nurse" by Margaret Cowling [n.d.], 1 Mimeographed TMs, 4 copies, 136 pp. (Box-folder 001-002)
- Roster of Base Hospital 41 personnel [n.d.], 1 Mimeograph from book, 5 copies, 25 pp. (Box-folder 001-003)
- Unit chronology and roster of Base Hospital 41 personnel 1976 November 11, 1 Mimeograph TMs, 1 mimeograph book excerpt, 10pp. (Box-folder 001-004)
- "Historical Sketch of Base Hospital 41" by Deming J. Shear; includes a "Red Cross Nurse" by Margaret Cowling [n.d.], 1 Mimeograph TMs, 34 pp. (Box-folder 001-005)
- Special Orders No. 70 1919, 1 Mimeograph TMs, 4 pp. (Box-folder 001-006)
  The orders list the officers and men required to report for duty on detached service at the American University, France
- Correspondence to and from former Base Hospital 41 members, re: reunion 1940 May-June, 1 ALS, 1 TLS, 1 Carbon copy TL, 3pp. (Box-folder 001-007)
  Letter from Glenn F. Clark to M. S. Byrd, Letter from Stuart S. Rothwell to Glenn F. Clark, Letter from C. C. Faires to Stuart S. Rothwell
- Correspondence to and from former Base Hospital 41 members, re: reunion 1941 March-April, 2 TL, 6TLS, 5 Carbon copy TL, 3ALS, 1AN, 20 pp. (Box-folder 001-008)
  Letter from Stuart S. Rothwell to Nate L. Adams, Letter from Stuart S. Rothwell to Glenn Updike, Letter from Stuart S. Rothwell to Bruce C. Lightner, Letter from Stuart S. Rothwell to A. V. Swann, Letter from Stuart S. Rothwell to Garland Perry, Letter from Stuart S. Rothwell to LeRoy Hyde, Letter from Randolph Blackford to Mason [S. Byrd], Letter from Randolph Blackford to Perry, Letter from Randolph Blackford to Walter, Letter from Randolph Blackford to Dettor, Letter from Randolph Blackford to Harry Wilson, Letter from Randolph Blackford to Harry Conduff, Letter from Nate to Stuart S. Rothwell, Letter from Bruce C. Lightner to Stuart S. Rothwell, Letter from LeRoy W. Hyde to Stuart S. Rothwell, Letter from G. B. Updike to Stuart S. Rothwell, Letter from Herbert Old to Mason [S. Byrd], Letter from Micajah Woods to M. S. Byrd, Letter from Sylvan B. Ney to M. S. Byrd, Letter from Garland Peery to M. S. Byrd, Letter from M. to Sylven B. Ney, Letter from M. to Micajah Woods, Letter from M. to Herbert Old, Letter from M. to Randolph L. Blackford, Letter from M. S. Byrd, R. H. Perry, W. S. Chisholm, W. T. Dettor, Harry Wilson, Harry Conduff and Stuart Rothwell to Comrade
- Correspondence to and from former Base Hospital 41 members, re: reunion and organization accounts 1941 May-June, 3 TLS, 2ALS, 2 Carbon copy TL, 2 Telegrams, 4 Bank deposit slips, 15 pp. (Box-folder 001-009)
  Letter from B. B. Leigh to Mason S. Byrd, Letter from H. T. Haley to M. S. Byrd, Letter from Sidney E. Powers to Mason S. Byrd, Letter from Bert Wood to Mason [Byrd], Telegram from Mary Stuart Goodwin to Mason F. Byrd, Telegram from Randolph H. Perry to Julian M. Cabell, Letter from Julian M. Cabell to [Randolph H.] Perry, 2 Letters from Randolph H. Perry to Julian M. Cabell
- Correspondence to and from former Base Hospital 41 members, re: reunion and reunion costs 1941 September-November, 3 TLS, 1 TMs, 1 Carbon copy TL, 3 Invoices, 1 Postcard w AN, 10 pp. (Box-folder 001-010)
  Letter from W. L. Younger to R. H. Perry, Letter from William Vansant to Stuart S. Rothwell, Postcard from Dorothy Marks to Stuart S. Rothwell, Letter from Beverly D. Tucker to Stuart S. Rothwell, Letter from Randolph H. Perry to W. L. Younger
- Correspondence to and from former Base Hospital 41 members, re: reunion 1942 April-June, 2 TLS, 5 Carbon copy TL, 1 ALS, 1 Bank check, 1 Postcard, 13 pp. (Box-folder 001-011)
  Letter from B. W. Rannells to Stuart S. Rothwell, Letter from Stuart S. Rothwell to B. W. Rannells, Letter from Stuart S. Rothwell to Clifford C. Faires, Letter from C. C. Faires to Stuart S. Rothwell, Letter from Randolph H. Perry to Sidney Powers, Letter from Clifford C. Faires to J. Malcolm Luck and Stuart [S. Rothwell], Letter from Andrew W. White to Stuart R. Rothwell, Letter from Stuart S. Rothwell to Andrew W. White, Postcard from Sidney E. Powers to Randolph H. Perry
- Correspondence to and from former Base Hospital 41 members, re: reunions 1955, 1958, 1959, 1 TLS, 1 Telegram, 1 ALS, 4 pp. (Box-folder 001-012)
  Telegram from Swann to Randolph H. Perry, Letter from Wood to Randolph H. Perry, Letter from W. Glenn Elliott to Bernard
- Correspondence to and from former Base Hospital 41 members, re: reunion; address lists 1963 August, 4 ALS, 4 TLS, 2 Postcards, 16 pp. (Box-folder 001-013)
  Postcard from Sidney E. Powers to Randolph H. Perry, Postcard from Sidney E. Powers to William E. Pinner, Letter from S. E. Powers to John, Letter from Sidney E. Powers to Pete [Randolph H. Perry], Letter from Sidney [E. Powers] to Pete [Randolph H. Perry], Letter from Sidney E. Powers to Comrade, Letter from Sidney [E. Powers] to Pete [Randolph H. Perry], Letter from Sidney E. P[owers] to Pete [Randolph H. Perry], Letter from S[idney] E. P[owers] to Pete [Randolph H. Perry], Letter from Dad [Clifford C. Faires] to Randolph H. Perry
- Correspondence to and from former Base Hospital 41 members, re: reunion 1963 September, 8 ALS, 9TLS, 4 Carbon copy TL, 1 TMs, 3 Postcards, 30 pp. (Box-folder 001-014)
  Letter from John Martin to Pete [Randolph H. Perry], Letter from Mason S. Byrd et. al. to Veterans of the Battle of Paris, Resolution by the Arizona Judges' Association upon the retirement of Clifford C. Faires, Letter from Sidney [E. Powers] to Pete [Randolph H. Perry], Letter from John H. Karsten to Randolph Perry, Letter from Randolph H. Perry to John H. Karsten, Letter from Randolph H. Perry to J. Richard Thomas, Letter from Randolph H. Perry to Nate L. Adams, Letter from Pete [Randolph H.] Perry et. al. to Veterans of Battle of Paris, Letter from Walter E. Haley to [Randolph H.] Perry, Letter from Sidney [E. Powers] to Pete [Randolph H. Perry], Letter from W. L. Younger to Pete [Randolph H. Perry], Letter from B. W. Rannells to R. H. Perry, Letter from Frank Nelson to Pete [Randolph H. Perry], Letter from Kenneth C. Patty to R. H. Perry, Postcard from Puss [J. Richard] Thomas to Pete [Randolph H. Perry], Postcard from W. D. Wright to Sidney E. Powers, Postcard from Randolph F. Blackford to Randolph H. Perry
- Correspondence to and from former Base Hospital 41 members, re: reunion 1963 October 1-2, 1 ALS, 4 TLS, 12 Carbon copy TL, 3 Postcards w AN, 23 pp. (Box-folder 001-015)
  Postcard from D. R. Armentrout to Randolph H. Perry, 2 Postcards from Sidney [E. Powers] to Randolph H. Perry, Letter from J. Leicester Watts to Randolph H. Perry, Letter from J. Leicester Watts to Randolph H. Perry, Letter from Randolph H. Perry to Deming J. Shear, Letter from Randolph H. Perry to B. W. Rannells, Letter from Randolph H. Perry to J. F. Nelson, Letter from B. B. Leigh to R. H. Perry, Letter from Randolph H. Perry to George S. Coyle, Letter from Randolph H. Perry to Harry R. Cline, Letter from Scott[ ] to Pete [Randolph H. Perry], Letter from Randolph H. Perry to Randolph F. Blackford, Letter from Randolph H. Perry to Walter E. Haley, Letter from Randolph H. Perry to W. D. Wright, Letter from Randolph H. Perry to Kenneth C. Patty, Letter from Randolph H. Perry to W. L. Younger, Letter from Randolph H. Perry to W. D. Wright, Letter from Randolph H. Perry to Sidney E. Powers, Letter from Randolph H. Perry to J. Leicester Watts, Letter from Jack, J. C. Curtis to R. H. Perry
- Correspondence to and from former Base Hospital 41 members, re: reunion 1963, October 3-19, 5 ALS, 4 TLS, 11 Carbon copy TL, 21 pp. (Box-folder 001-016)
  Letter from Bruce C. Lightner to R. H. Perry, Letter from Randolph H. Perry to Bruce C. Lightner, Letter from Randolph H. Perry to B. B. Leigh, Letter from Randolph H. Perry to John C. Curtis, Letter from Randolph H. Perry to Alfred Martin, Letter from Harry M. Wilson to Pete [Randolph H. Perry], Letter from Randolph H. Perry to Harry M. Wilson, Letter from J. Leicester Watts to Randolph H. Perry, Letter from Sylvan B. Ney to R. H. Perry, Letter from Beverley D. Tucker to R. H. Perry, Letter from Deming J. Shear to R. H. Perry, Letter from Randolph H. Perry to J. Leicester Watts, Letter from Randolph H. Perry to Deming J. Shear, Letter from Randolph H. Perry to Sylvan B. Ney, Letter from Randolph H. Perry to Beverley D. Tucker, Letter from Randolph H. Perry to D. R. Armentrout, Letter from Fred Terrell to Randolph H. Perry, Letter from Randolph H. Perry to Fred Terrell, Letter from Carroll Eugene Beach to R. H. Perry, Letter from William N. Jones to R. H. Perry
- Correspondence to and from former Base Hospital 41 members, re: reunion 1963 October 20-27, 6 ALS, 9 TLS, 9 Carbon copy TL, 25 pp. (Box-folder 001-017)
  Letter from Joe Messinger to Pete [Randolph H. Perry], Letter from Jack [John H. Karsten to R. H. Perry, Letter from Randolph H. Perry to Sidney E. Powers, Letter from Malcolm W. Bryan to Pete [Randolph H. Perry], Letter from D. D. Vance to Pete R. H. Perry, Letter from Randolph H. Perry to Carroll E. Beach, Letter from Jack W. Gourley, Letter from Sidney E. Powers to Pete [Randolph H. Perry], Letter from Randolph H. Perry to John H. Karsten, Letter from Randolph H. Perry to Elbert E. Rush, Letter from Randolph H. Perry to Malcolm W. Bryan, Letter from Sam L. Brown to Pete R. H. Perry, Letter from Randolph H. Perry to Joseph Messinger, Letter from Randolph H. Perry to D. D. Vance, Letter from Randolph H. Perry to Sidney E. Powers, Letter from Nate L. Adams, Letter from Randolph H. Perry to S. L. Brown, Letter from Ned Carrington to Pete [Randolph H. Perry], Letter from Fred W. St. Clair to R. H. Perry, Letter from Harry R. Cline to Randolph Perry, Letter from Woodford B. Llackley to Pete [Randolph H. Perry], Letter from Wilbert T. Woodson to Pete [Randolph H. Perry], Letter from J. Scott Atkinson to Pete [Randolph H. Perry], Letter from Fred W. St. Clair to Sidney E. Powers
- Correspondence to and from former Base Hospital 41 members, re: reunion 1963 October 28-30, 2 ALS, 2 TLS, 10 Carbon copy TL, 14 pp. (Box-folder 001-018)
  Letter from Randolph H. Perry to Edward L. Carrington, Letter from Randolph H. Perry to Fred W. St. Clair, Letter from Randolph H. Perry to Nate L. Adams, Letter from Randolph H. Perry to J. W. Gourley, Letter from Jack to Pete [Randolph H. Perry], Letter from William G. Vansant to Randolph H. Perry, Letter from Bill Hankins to R. H. Perry, Letter from Sidney E. Powers to Pete [Randolph H. Perry], Letter from Randolph H. Perry to William N. Jones, Letter from Randolph H. Perry to J. Scott Atkinson, Letter from Randolph H. Perry to Woodford B. Hackley, Letter from Randolph H. Perry to John H. Karsten, Letter from Randolph H. Perry to William G. Vansant, Letter from Randolph H. Perry to Wilbert T. Woodson
- Correspondence to and from former Base Hospital 41 members, re: reunion 1963 November 1-5, 5 ALS, 3 TLS, 11 Carbon copy TL, 4 Mimeograph TLS (4 copies), 1 Postcard, 25 pp. (Box-folder 001-019)
  Postcard from J. L. Hawkins to [Randolph H.] Perry, Letter from George S. Coyle to Pete [Randolph H. Perry], Letter from George S. Coyle to Pete [Randolph H. Perry], Letter from Randolph H. Perry to Harry R. Cline, Letter from Randolph H. Perry to Sidney E. Powers, Letter from Randolph H. Perry to William E. Hankins, Letter from Grover C. Ross to R. H. Perry, Letter from Joe E. Currell to Pete [Randolph H. Perry], Letter from J. E. Newman to R. H. Perry, Letter from Frank Passwaters to R. H. Perry, Letter from Randolph H. Perry to H. A. Goodwin, Letter from Randolph H. Perry to J. L. Hawkins, Letter from Randolph H. Perry to Frank Passwaters, Letter from Randolph H. Perry to Grover C. Ross, Letter from Kenneth W. Livesay to Randolph H. Perry, Letter from A. V. Swann to Randolph H. Perry, Letter from Randolph H. Perry to to Joseph E. Currell, Letter from Randolph H. Perry to A. B. Swann, Letter from Randolph H. Perry to Douglas D. Vance, Letter from Randolph H. Perry to J. E. Newman, Letter from Randolph H. Perry to Veterans of Battle of Paris
- Correspondence to and from former Base Hospital 41 members, re: reunion 1963 November 6-7, 3 ALS, 5 TLS, 5 Carbon copy TL, 14 pp. (Box-folder 001-020)
  Letter from Bruce C. Lightner to Randolph H. Perry, Letter from Sidney [E. Powers] to Pete [Randolph H. Perry], Letter from R. E. Dyche to R. H. Perry, Letter from Glenn B. Updike to Randolph H. Perry, Letter from Randolph H. Perry to Kenneth W. Livesay, Letter from Randolph H. Perry to Glenn B. Updike, Letter from Randolph H. Perry to Bruce C. Lightner, Letter from Randolph H. Perry to Sidney E. Powers, Letter from Randolph H. Perry to Robert E. Dyche, Letter from Nell Williams to R. H. Perry, Letter from J. C. Curtis to R. H. Perry, Letter from J. F. Nelson to Pete [Randolph H. Perry], Letter from Harry R. Cline to R. H. Perry
- Correspondence to and from former Base Hospital 41 members, re: reunion 1963 November 8-18, 8 TLS, 17 Carbon copy TL, 1 Telegram, 3 Postcards, 32 pp. (Box-folder 001-021)
  Postcard from A. V. Swann to Randolph Perry, Postcard from Lee Hendrick to R. H. Perry, Postcard from Bill Jones to R. H. Perry, Letter from Randolph H. Perry to J. F. Nelson, Letter from Randolph H. Perry to Harry R. Cline, Letter from Alfred Martin to Randolph H. Perry, Letter from B. W. Rannells to R. H. Perry, Letter from Randolph H. Perry to Alfred N. Martin, Letter from Randolph H. Perry to Nell Williams, Letter from Randolph H. Perry to Fritz L. Hardin, Letter from Randolph H. Perry to J. C. Curtis, Letter from Randolph H. Perry to George S. Coyle, Letter from Mac Bryan to Pete [Randolph H. Perry], Letter from D. D. Vance to R. H. Perry, Letter from Sidney E. Powers to Pete [Randolph H. Perry], Letter from Randolph H. Perry to to A. V. Swann, Telegram from Dad Farris [Clifford C. Faires], Letter from Randolph H. Perry to Sidney E. Powers, Letter from Randolph H. Perry to B. W. Rannells, Letter from Randolph H. Perry to Malcolm W. Bryan, Letter from Mason S. Byrd to R. H. Perry, Letter from Glenn B. Updike to R. H. Perry, Letter from W. L. Younger to R. H. Perry, Letter from Randolph H. Perry to William T. Jones, Letter from Randolph H. Perry to Harvey A. Goodwin, Letter from Randolph H. Perry to Russell M. Sexton, Letter from Randolph H. Perry to Elbert E. Rush, Letter from Randolph H. Perry to Clifford C. Faires, Letter from Randolph H. Perry to Alex G. St. Clair
- Correspondence to and from former Base Hospital 41 members, re: reunion 1963 November 19-December 9, 3 ALS, 4TLS, 9 Carbon copy TL, 18 pp. (Box-folder 001-022)
  Letter from Randolph H. Perry to Sidney E. Powers, Letter from Ben B. Leigh to Randolph H. Perry, Letter from Fred Terrell to Randolph H. Perry, Letter from Sidney [E. Powers] to Pete [Randolph H. Perry], Letter from George S. Coyle to Pete [Randolph H. Perry], Letter from Randolph H. Perry to George S. Coyle, Letter from B. W. Rannells to Randolph H. Perry, Letter to C. C. Faires to Pete [Randolph H. Perry], Letter from Randolph H. Perry to B. B. Leigh, Letter from Randolph H. Perry to Glenn B. Updike, Letter from Randolph H. Perry to W. L. Younger, Letter from Randolph H. Perry to Fred Terrell, Letter from Randolph H. Perry to Sidney E. Powers, Letter from Randolph H. Perry to B. W. Rannells, Letter from Mary Stuart Goodwin to Pete [Randolph H. Perry], Letter from Randolph H. Perry to Mrs. William H. Goodwin
- Correspondence to and from former Base Hospital 41 members, re: reunion 1965 December-1965 February, 5 ALS, 2 TLS, 7 Carbon copy TL, 3 Postcards, 1 AL, 26 pp. (Box-folder 001-023)
  Letter from Sidney E. Powers to Pete [Randolph H. Perry], Postcard from Pete [Randolph H. Perry] to Bernard P. Chamberlain, Letter from Catherine Karsten to [Bernard P.] Chamberlain, List of returned cards, Letter to Sidney E. Powers, Lettter from Sidney [E. Powers] to Pete [Randolph H. Perry], Letter from Randolph H. Perry to Sidney E. Powers, Letter to Sid[ney E. Powers], Letter from Sidney [E. Powers] to Pete [Randolph H. Perry], List of returned letters, Letter from Mrs. W. R. Kiley to Randolph Perry, Postcard from Sidney [E. Powers] to R. H. Perry, Postcard to Randolph H. Perry, Letter from Sidney E. Powers to members of Base Hospital 41, Letter to Sidney E. Powers, Letter from Randolph H. Perry to Sidney E. Powers, Letter to Sidney E. Powers, Letter from Sidney [E. Powers] to Pete [Randolph H. Perry]
- Correspondence to and from former Base Hospital 41 members, re: reunion 1965 March-April, 2 ALS, 1 TL, 2 TLS, Mimeograph and Carbon copy 8 TL and 2 TLS, 19 pp. (Box-folder 001-024)
  Letter from Randolph H. Perry to Sidney E. Powers, Letter from Sidney [E. Powers] to Pete [Randolph H. Perry], Letter from William N. Jones to R. H. Perry, Letter from Randolph H. Perry to Grady R. Henry, Letter from Randolph H. Perry to William N. Jones, Letter from Randolph H. Perry to Sidney E. Powers, Letter from Randolph H. Perry to Sidney E. Powers, Letter from B. B. Leigh to Sidney E. Powers, Letter from Sidney [E. Powers] to Pete [Randolph H. Perry], Letter from the Reunion Committee to Ambulatory Veterans of Battle of Paris, Letter from Nate D. Page to Pete [Randolph H. Perry], Letter from Fred Terrell to Mason S. Byrd, Letter from Bernard P. Chamberlain to Mrs. John H. Karston
- Correspondence to and from former Base Hospital 41 members, re: reunion 1965 May-June, 4 ALS, 5 TLS, 1 Postcard, 11 Carbon copy TL, 1 Telegram w AN, 29 pp. (Box-folder 001-025)
  Letter from Deming J. Shear to Pete [Randolph H. Perry], Letter from Randolph H. Perry to Ruby Shaner, Letter from Randolph H. Perry to Nate L. Adams, Letter from Randolph H. Perry to E. G. Purvis, Letter from B. B. Leigh to Randolph H. Perry, Letter from Randolph H. Perry to B. B. Leigh, Letter from Scott Atkinson to Pete [Randolph H. Perry], Letter from Bernard W. Rannells to [Randolph H. Perry], Letter from J. F. Nelson to Pete [Randolph H. Perry], Letter from Randolph H. Perry to Scott Atkinson, Letter from Randolph H. Perry to B. W. Rannells, Letter from Randolph H. Perry to J. F. Nelson, Telegram from Clifford C. Faires to Pete [Randloph H.] Perry, Letter from Sidney E. Powers to Comrades and Friends of Base Hospital 41, Letter from Randolph H. Perry to to Clifford C. Faires, Letter from Randolph H. Perry to Sidney E. Powers, Letter from Glenn B. Updike to Randolph H. Perry, Letter from George S. Coyle to the Reunion Committee, Letter from Randolph H. Perry to George S. Coyle, Letter from Randolph H. Perry to Glenn B. Updike, Postcard from J. Scott Atkinson to Randolph H. Perry
- Correspondence to and from former Base Hospital 41 members, re: reunion 1966 February-March, 4 ALS, 1AMs, Carbon copy 4 TL and 2TLS, 18 pp. (Box-folder 001-026)
  Letter from Sidney E. Powers to the Nurses, Officers and Enlisted Personnel, Letter from John to Sid[ney E. Powers], Letter from Randolph H. Perry to Sidney E. Powers, Letter from Sidney [E. Powers] to Pete [Randolph H. Perry], Memo of list of names and addresses, Letter from Randolph H. Perry to Sidney E. Powers, Letter from Sidney [E. Powers] to Pete [Randolph H. Perry], Letter from Randolph H. Perry to Sidney E. Powers, Letter from Sidney [E. Powers] to Pete [Randolph H. Perry], Letter from Randolph H. Perry to Sidney E. Powers, Letter from Sidney [E. Powers] to Pete [Randolph H. Perry]